<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Res701 on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/res701/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Res701 on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/res701/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 10</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-10/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Conclusion Well it has come to that time. It&amp;rsquo;s near the end of the semester and it&amp;rsquo;s time to write the final blog. This blog is a reflection of the res701 class. To be honest of all the classes, res701 is one of my favorites. There were a lot of things that made me think and made me question more than usual. Especially the day when we discussed knowing and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 9</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-9/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Copyright vs Copyleft Todays class was around creative commons, which is a permissive license designed as a better alternative to copyright. We were shown a video which covered how copying is not stealing. Makes sense if you think about it. Copying is taking something and making a duplicate of it, where as stealing is taking something and leaving nothing.
There is a website called choosealicense which clearly describes the use cases/scenarios that a certain license would cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 8</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-8/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Ethics This class was on ethics in research. We started by discussing the difference between morals and ethics. The difference that we concluded was that morals are derived from an individual, whereas ethics are derived from society.
The tutor showed us an experiement called the milgram experiment, which I had never heard of before. It was a study around how individuals will do things that go against their morals or ethics if told to do the said thing by an authorative figure (a researcher in this case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 7</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-7/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Project Proposal Peer Review Todays blog is around reviewing another classmates project proposal. There are quite a lot of good proposals, but the one that I have chosen to review is Stewart&amp;rsquo;s project proposal. His proposal is about building a neural network to recognize and classify a face in an image. The activities he has listed are as follows.
 Read an academic article on face detection Research computer vision and find relevant articles Research academic articles on computer vision Lynda courses  Neural networks and convolutional neural networks essential training Deep learning: face recognition Classify images and detect recognition  CourseRA tutorials  Convolutional neural networks  Exploring and using Azure&amp;rsquo;s cloud based face or computer vision services  As I have a bias for AI, I like this proposal and am glad to see a classmate interested in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 6</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-6/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Interests and non-interests in IT One of the topics that we discussed today in class was things about IT that interest me and the things that don&amp;rsquo;t interest me. We were given the following questions to answer in no more than 10 words.
 The IT area/subject I have most enjoyed is Software development
The IT area/subject I least enjoyed is Systems analysis and design (SYD)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 5</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-5/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Analyzing Academic Articles Todays blog is about reading and understanding one of the academic articles that I chose for the previous blog. We are to answer the following questions around the article.
 Did the abstract tell you three things I said it should? If not what did it tell you?
 What seems to be the research question(s) they were trying to answer?
 What method(s) did they use to answer the question(s)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-4/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Academic Publishing Today&amp;rsquo;s blog is about finding two academic research papers of my choice, which as stated in the first res701 blog will be around data science, machine learning, or deep learning. I stumbled across a gentleman by the name of Jürgen Schmidhuber when watching a video on a panel of specialists talking about the current state of AI. At the time I had no clue who he was or what his accomplishments were, but came to know that he was behind the publication of LSTM (long short-term memory) architectures and also the advancements in CNN (convolutional neural networks) architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-3/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Credibility How can something be credible? Both the oxford dictionary and merriam-webster define credibility as &amp;ldquo;the quality of being believable&amp;rdquo; [source 1] [source 2] This to me is rather dangerous, since things like vaccine hesitancy have gained traction in recent years. This stems from social platforms giving an amplified voice to those who are not credible, but are accepted as credible by others using the social platform(s) for their source(s) of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-2/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Paradigms Postmodernism is a word that I have heard people like Jordan Peterson use but is not a word that I never investigated. It just so happens that postmodernism is one of the paradigms that we talked about in class. The other paradigms are classical and social. One of the take homes is to choose one of the paradigms, describe it, explain what it can be used for, and why I like/dislike the paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-1/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Ontology &amp;amp; Epistemology Today in class the tutor had a set of questions that he wanted us to break up into groups and answer. Reflecting on these questions has only increased the amount questions rather than provide truthful or even a slightly understandable answers. In saying that they are also extremely interesting questions that have a much deeper meaning than anyone could ever percieve or come to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-0/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Day 0 Res701 is another required class for my bachelor of IT course. This class is based around academic research, where we look at/review academic papers/research methodologies and write blogs about them. Blogs have never been my strong point so I am going to put 110% effort into ensuring consistentcy for this class. I already know what area I am going to be focusing on (data science, machine learning and deep learning), so in that regard I am already ahead of the curve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>