<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:17:28 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/shell-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:17:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/shell-0/</guid>
      <description>Unix Shell It has been almost 3 years since I made the the switch to Linux, and have enjoyed every moment. Like most, I found the terminal to be a daunting thing at first, much like Linux itself. I quickly discovered how much more I enjoyed using a terminal over GUI applications. Though I have gotten by over the past years with the basic commands like cd or rm, I never really dedicated time to improving my skills with the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/arch-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 06:15:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/arch-0/</guid>
      <description>Arch ~ A VirtualBox Installation Arch Linux is one of those things that I&amp;rsquo;ve known about for a long time but have never really gotten around to exploring. I have used manjaro before, which was introduced to me by my friend Sam, but have never used/installed vanilla Arch. This blog is going to cover the steps to setup vanilla Arch using this installation guide which was suggested to me by zer0the0ry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quake3 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/quake3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 08:31:38 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/quake3-0/</guid>
      <description>Quake 3 ~ ioquake3 I&amp;rsquo;ve covered DOOM in one of my previous blogs. In this blog I am going to cover how to get Quake 3 arena running. The source port I am going to use is ioquake3. Unlike DOOM, there is no entirely free version of Quake 3. Quake 3 requires .pak files, which can found in the game files after purchasing Quake 3 on steam.
The following dependencies are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alacritty 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/alacritty-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:36:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/alacritty-0/</guid>
      <description>Alacritty If you use Linux then most likely you also use a terminal. One of the things that I still have not gotten used to after switching from windows is how customizable Linux really is. In this case the terminal. The first thing I asked myself when I came across Alacritty is &amp;ldquo;why?&amp;rdquo;. It never clicked until rwxrob made a comment about how he was using Alacritty as his terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/vim-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 08:27:35 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/vim-0/</guid>
      <description>Vim I was first introduced to Vim by my good friend Sam. As someone who tries to work as much in the terminal as possible, Vim was perfect for my text editing needs. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve known/used Vim for a while, it&amp;rsquo;s always basic usage for quick edititing, and its always been a secondary editor to Visual Studio Code. This was because I relied heavily on the intellisense when programming in langauges like Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega2 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:46:09 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</guid>
      <description>Onion Omega 2 During a Python meetup one of my tutors Mark showed me a new device he had purchased from kickstarter called the onion omega 2. All that I knew at the time was that it was a smaller version of a raspberry pi. When I first got my hands on one I found out it was so much more under the hood. The first things to note is the unit itself needs another component (a dock).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/doom-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 11:20:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/doom-0/</guid>
      <description>DOOM DOOM is easily (in my opinion), one of the most iconic games ever made. It is enjoyable to play even to this day. The best part of DOOM is the fact that it has been made open source under a GPL license. From this there have been many source ports of the original DOOM code. I particularly like gzdoom as it adds graphics rending features, but there are quite a few that all have their own unique additions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ai-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 23:41:56 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ai-0/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence This is going to be the first of many blogs that I am excited to write as this topic is what peeks my interest within the IT industry and never ceases to amaze me. I was introduced to the field by my good friend Krupesh, who was also the one that got me into Python back in 2017. Since then I knew that my dream career would be within the field of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bmus</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</guid>
      <description>Bmus ~ Back Me Up Scotty Taking backups of devices is something that more often than not people don&amp;rsquo;t do, and this includes myself. Prior to my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s I never took backups or even thought about them. Looking back I reee internally everytime I think about how much I would have lost if something had happened to my laptops or desktops over the years. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like the 2015 me, take regular backups&amp;hellip; Ever since a friend of mine, Nick got me into Linux I have been learning new things everyday, from built in commands, to the various things that can be done from the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partitioning</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/partitioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/partitioning/</guid>
      <description>Partitioning Partitioning? No not mathematics partitions, computer partitions. More specifically hardware partitions (in my case a microSD card). I am officially put off GUIs and am taking a hiatus from them. My raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s microSDD card isn&amp;rsquo;t being used at the moment, so I am formatting it to be used as storage for pcap files that I am capturing on my network. Perfect time to learn how to partition drives from the terminal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmux</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/tmux/</guid>
      <description>Tmux - Terminal Multiplexer If you&amp;rsquo;re like me then you use a terminal a lot. If you were me 20 minutes ago then you would also have multiple terminal tabs open with various applications running. I had heard of an application from some of my peers before about the ability to open multiple terminal panes within the same terminal window. For a while I didn&amp;rsquo;t look into it, but then (about 20 minutes ago) I had enough of swapping between terminal tabs and the editor I had been using (vscode).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>