<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryla on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/ryla/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ryla on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/ryla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 5</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-5/</guid>
      <description>Day 6 Today was the final day of the RYLA trip. No personal training today, just the usual banana/apple for breakfast then straight into speakers.
The first speaker of the day was Kingseley, the event organizer and another favorite of mine. His talk was on gaining information, something I strive to do everyday. There are various ways of gathering information, a few examples can be found below &amp;hellip;
 Reading Listening/watching videos Talking to people Interviewing  Then he explained the various types of questions which include but are not limited to &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-4/</guid>
      <description>Day 5 After needed sleep and again waking up to the usual 7am personal training and a breakfast of a banana/apple. The first speaker of the day was another favorite, Michelle Sharp, the CEO of Kilmarnock. Kilmarnock is a social enterprise (started by Christobel Robinson), which by Michelle&amp;rsquo;s definition is a business model that takes on social issues. She told us about the story of how after 50+ years, Kilmarnock was about to close its doors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-3/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 Today as normal we woke and gathered at 7am for personal training, though today&amp;rsquo;s pt was just yoga (which was actually really nice). Then for breakfast I ate the usually banana and apple. Today was the high-ropes course, which I was rather excited for since I had never done something like that before. The first thing we did when we got their was put sunscreen on cause damn it was hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 The morning started of the same as the previous, we all woke and gathered at 7am for personal training with Honour, but this time she delegated 2 people to be the ones to organize the exercises. Our group was with Demi who had a great warm up idea where we had to run around in a circle and when she said a command we had to do the appropriate animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-1/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 The morning started at 7am where we would do personal training with Honour. Then afterwards was morning breakfast. I am not one who usually eats breakfast, but I figured I would need the energy so I ate a banana. Our first speaker of the day was a person from the NZ defense force. I will have to re-iterate this section with his name as I cannot remember it and didn&amp;rsquo;t take the opprotunity to write it down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-0/</guid>
      <description>Rotary Youth Leadership Association ~ Day 1 Rotary is a group of individuals that come together and help the local community through various means. Both of my parents are active members of the Wakatu Nelson branch, where they meet every Friday morning at 7am. I have been a few times and have enjoyed myself everytime. One of the members, Delise, told me about this camp of sorts called RYLA (Rotary Youth Leadership Association).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>