<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serverless on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/serverless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serverless on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 22</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Deploying with Digital Ocean Now that we have built the function, which was covered in the last post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy it. For deployment we will be using digital ocean for a couple of reasons. First it&amp;rsquo;s much easier than setting up instances in the larger cloud providers like GCP, AWS, or Azure. Second digital ocean has an OpenFaas one-click droplet.
The first thing to do is to ssh into the droplet via ssh root@&amp;lt;IP address&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 21</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-21/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas ~ Creating a Function With assessment 2 finished now it&amp;rsquo;s time to focus back on assessment 3, which serverless via OpenFaas. In this blog I am going to create the function, and it will be with a program I&amp;rsquo;ve already made; sbh. The first thing to do is create a new directory to store the code in, this will be done via mkdir web701.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 11</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-11/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas ~ Lab 4 In this blog we are going to go through lab 4 which goes into more depth around functions.
The first part of the lab covers configuration injection with environment variables. There are two ways of doing so; at deployment time and using query string and HTTP headers. Environment variables at deployment time are covered in lab 3 when working with write_debug, which is where the environment variable is added to the YAML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 10</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-10/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas Continued ~ Lab 3 In this blog we are going to explore the OpenFaas workshop. Since we already have OpenFaas deployed and running from the previous blog, we are going to skip to lab 3; introduction to functions. OpenFaas provides two ways of creating a new function; using a template, or using an existing binary. I dont have a binary to use, so I am going to be using a template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 9</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-9/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas As stated in the previous blog, the first exposure to serverless was OpenFaaS. Whether its because of bias of the first exposure or because of bias towards docker, I am going to be exploring OpenFaaS for the serverless implementation of assessment three. First thing to do like anything is to head to the documentation section. &amp;ldquo;OpenFaaS (Functions as a Service) is a framework for building serverless functions with Docker and Kubernetes which has first class support for metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 8</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-8/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Serverless For the third assessment we are to choose a web technology to research and implement. It has to be web related, so one of the things that came up when discussing with my tutor was exploring serverless architectures. I have been exposed to serverless before when I was browsing through /r/opensource and came across OpenFaaS. Before we dive any deeper lets come to an understanding of what we really mean when we are talking about serverless.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>