<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:46:09 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega2 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:46:09 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</guid>
      <description>Onion Omega 2 During a Python meetup one of my tutors Mark showed me a new device he had purchased from kickstarter called the onion omega 2. All that I knew at the time was that it was a smaller version of a raspberry pi. When I first got my hands on one I found out it was so much more under the hood. The first things to note is the unit itself needs another component (a dock).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 5 ~ Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-5/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Proxmox Networking is one of the IT sectors that I have yet to spend much time in. My only exposure has been a NET501 class where we covered the basics of things like booting a virtual machine, routers/IPs, certificates, dhcp, and a few others. Since then I haven&amp;rsquo;t really touched anything to do with networking except for creation/use of virtual machines on the cloud platforms (GCP, AWS and Azure).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 2 ~ Azure</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Azure Part of the stack that is being used for this project is Azure. I am not a fan of microsoft so my opinion on anything to do with them is not positive. This is the cloud provider that Krupesh has chosen to go with however, so I will learn it anyway. Azure (like most cloud providers) gives 200 credits which are only valid for 30 days (GCP and AWS are both a year).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>