<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:17:28 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/shell-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:17:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/shell-0/</guid>
      <description>Unix Shell It has been almost 3 years since I made the the switch to Linux, and have enjoyed every moment. Like most, I found the terminal to be a daunting thing at first, much like Linux itself. I quickly discovered how much more I enjoyed using a terminal over GUI applications. Though I have gotten by over the past years with the basic commands like cd or rm, I never really dedicated time to improving my skills with the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/arch-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 06:15:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/arch-0/</guid>
      <description>Arch ~ A VirtualBox Installation Arch Linux is one of those things that I&amp;rsquo;ve known about for a long time but have never really gotten around to exploring. I have used manjaro before, which was introduced to me by my friend Sam, but have never used/installed vanilla Arch. This blog is going to cover the steps to setup vanilla Arch using this installation guide which was suggested to me by zer0the0ry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:34:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-1/</guid>
      <description>Nginx ~ Subdomains and a Blog In the previous blog we explored serving a Go web application with Nginx on Digital Ocean. This blog is going to cover how to host a static website on a subdomain. One of the things I did not cover in the last blog is how to point to your domain name with Digital Ocean. For more on this please refer to this blog that I found/used originally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quake3 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/quake3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 08:31:38 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/quake3-0/</guid>
      <description>Quake 3 ~ ioquake3 I&amp;rsquo;ve covered DOOM in one of my previous blogs. In this blog I am going to cover how to get Quake 3 arena running. The source port I am going to use is ioquake3. Unlike DOOM, there is no entirely free version of Quake 3. Quake 3 requires .pak files, which can found in the game files after purchasing Quake 3 on steam.
The following dependencies are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:12:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</guid>
      <description>Nginx ~ Deploying a Go Web Application Nginx is another one of those technologies that I&amp;rsquo;ve known of for a while, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to dig into. This blog will cover how to deploy a basic Golang web application on a $5/month ubuntu 18.04 vm hosted by Digital Ocean. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a really good blog by Michael Okoh which is what I am going to learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alacritty 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/alacritty-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:36:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/alacritty-0/</guid>
      <description>Alacritty If you use Linux then most likely you also use a terminal. One of the things that I still have not gotten used to after switching from windows is how customizable Linux really is. In this case the terminal. The first thing I asked myself when I came across Alacritty is &amp;ldquo;why?&amp;rdquo;. It never clicked until rwxrob made a comment about how he was using Alacritty as his terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/vim-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 08:27:35 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/vim-0/</guid>
      <description>Vim I was first introduced to Vim by my good friend Sam. As someone who tries to work as much in the terminal as possible, Vim was perfect for my text editing needs. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve known/used Vim for a while, it&amp;rsquo;s always basic usage for quick edititing, and its always been a secondary editor to Visual Studio Code. This was because I relied heavily on the intellisense when programming in langauges like Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega2 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:46:09 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</guid>
      <description>Onion Omega 2 During a Python meetup one of my tutors Mark showed me a new device he had purchased from kickstarter called the onion omega 2. All that I knew at the time was that it was a smaller version of a raspberry pi. When I first got my hands on one I found out it was so much more under the hood. The first things to note is the unit itself needs another component (a dock).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/doom-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 11:20:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/doom-0/</guid>
      <description>DOOM DOOM is easily (in my opinion), one of the most iconic games ever made. It is enjoyable to play even to this day. The best part of DOOM is the fact that it has been made open source under a GPL license. From this there have been many source ports of the original DOOM code. I particularly like gzdoom as it adds graphics rending features, but there are quite a few that all have their own unique additions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ai-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 23:41:56 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ai-0/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence This is going to be the first of many blogs that I am excited to write as this topic is what peeks my interest within the IT industry and never ceases to amaze me. I was introduced to the field by my good friend Krupesh, who was also the one that got me into Python back in 2017. Since then I knew that my dream career would be within the field of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goccer</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/goccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 20:27:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/goccer/</guid>
      <description>Goccer ~ Go Concurrent Web Crawler In one of the classes during my bachelor of IT, I started making my first program in Golang. That first program is what is now know as goccer. The idea behind the program was inspired by my fascination of web crawling. This blog is not going to cover every part of goccer, but will cover the key components. It will also cover the issues I ran into and the solution(s) that I used to overcome the problem(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 22:02:59 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-4/</guid>
      <description>C++ ~ CMake In-Depth In C++ 1, my examples had both a system defined header (&amp;lt;iostream&amp;gt;) and a user defined header (hello.h). In this blog we are going to cover headers in more detail. Most of the information in this blog is from a book called C++ in a nutshell, any other sources will be listed following the information.
Standard Library Headers There are 51 headers in the standard library which are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 08:37:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-3/</guid>
      <description>C++ ~ Grasping the Basics In the previous blogs I have just dived straight into programming in C++. This blog is going to focus around getting a better understanding of the language itself, including the various components that make up the language. It will cover the basics so for an experienced C++ programmer this blog will not be very interesting. If you are like me and new to C++ however, this blog may be beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 15:22:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-2/</guid>
      <description>C++ ~ OpenCV OpenCV is a library that I will be working with in C++, so this blog is going to be dedicated to installing OpenCV and setting it up for C++. The steps I will be following are the ones found on the linux tutorial section of the OpenCV website.
To start, we need to install the following dependancies.
sudo apt install build-essential \ cmake \ git \ libgtk2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 09:30:37 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-1/</guid>
      <description>C++ ~ Make and CMake One of the things Sam suggested to learn/use with C++ is make and cmake. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across make before, but not cmake. This blog is going to be about learning the basics of both make and cmake, as well as creating simple example projects with them.
The following is a simple program that I made to start with make.
// main.cpp #include &amp;quot;hello.h&amp;quot; int main() { Hello h; h.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello_c&#43;&#43;.cpp</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 06:17:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/cpp-0/</guid>
      <description>C++ For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to dive into a lower language such as C++, but never found the time to do so. Now I have an excuse as my new employment involves working with C++. To start, like with anything I made a simple hello world program. This looks like the following&amp;hellip;
#include &amp;lt;iostream&amp;gt; int main() { std::cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;quot;Hello world from C++!\n&amp;quot;; return 0; }  Now to compile the program via g++ main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ss-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ss-1/</guid>
      <description>Self Study 1 With the first semester of the last year finished the 2 week break has begun. I am very close to graduating, only 2 more electives to complete. Not entirely sure what electives I am going to choose as of yet, but I do know that I want to get into a good routine now that my bachelor degree is nearing the end. I have created a daily schedule which I am going to follow for ideally the rest of my life that I believe will be utilizing the most of the time I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 22</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Deploying with Digital Ocean Now that we have built the function, which was covered in the last post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy it. For deployment we will be using digital ocean for a couple of reasons. First it&amp;rsquo;s much easier than setting up instances in the larger cloud providers like GCP, AWS, or Azure. Second digital ocean has an OpenFaas one-click droplet.
The first thing to do is to ssh into the droplet via ssh root@&amp;lt;IP address&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 10</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-10/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Conclusion Well it has come to that time. It&amp;rsquo;s near the end of the semester and it&amp;rsquo;s time to write the final blog. This blog is a reflection of the res701 class. To be honest of all the classes, res701 is one of my favorites. There were a lot of things that made me think and made me question more than usual. Especially the day when we discussed knowing and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 9</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-9/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Copyright vs Copyleft Todays class was around creative commons, which is a permissive license designed as a better alternative to copyright. We were shown a video which covered how copying is not stealing. Makes sense if you think about it. Copying is taking something and making a duplicate of it, where as stealing is taking something and leaving nothing.
There is a website called choosealicense which clearly describes the use cases/scenarios that a certain license would cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 8</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-8/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Ethics This class was on ethics in research. We started by discussing the difference between morals and ethics. The difference that we concluded was that morals are derived from an individual, whereas ethics are derived from society.
The tutor showed us an experiement called the milgram experiment, which I had never heard of before. It was a study around how individuals will do things that go against their morals or ethics if told to do the said thing by an authorative figure (a researcher in this case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 21</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-21/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas ~ Creating a Function With assessment 2 finished now it&amp;rsquo;s time to focus back on assessment 3, which serverless via OpenFaas. In this blog I am going to create the function, and it will be with a program I&amp;rsquo;ve already made; sbh. The first thing to do is create a new directory to store the code in, this will be done via mkdir web701.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 20</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-20/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Heroku and Web Hosting We wrapped up the web implementation in the last blog with the addition of the auction system. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy the website to a web hosting service. There are two options that are available for the deployment, my tutors remote server, or a PaaS (Platform as a Service) provider like Heroku.
I want to get experience in both so I will deploy on both, but since the dependancies I require for the website are not yet installed on the tutor&amp;rsquo;s server I will start with deploying on Heroku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 19</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-19/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Auction System (cont.) In the last blog we covered authentication with the TradeMe API. After some playing around, I hit a wall with the list an item API method. Instead of wasting time trying to figure it out I am going to implement a simple dummy auction system. This is partly because I&amp;rsquo;d rather have something for an auction system than nothing and also partly because I have more important projects to work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 18</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-18/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Auction System With the authentication and calculator finished its now time to implement the auction system. For this feature I am going to be implementing it using the TradeMe API. This is partially because there is no existing auction extension in django and partially because I love API&amp;rsquo;s and this is a perfect opportunity to get experience integrating one.
The first thing to do is to head over and read the registering an application section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 17</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-17/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Price Calculator In the previous blog we implememented the functionality around editing and updating the user profile. Now that we have completed that feature requirement for the assessment, now it&amp;rsquo;s time to implement another of the feature requirements; the price calculator.
To start we are going to create a new app called calculator to keep things cleaner and easier. We do this by django-admin startapp calculator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 16</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-16/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Profile (editing) Last blog covered extending the user model of Django to add additional fields and then implementing a profile page. In this blog we are going to cover editing and updating the profile information. The first thing to do is to add the following to the urlpatterns variable in the urls.py file.
path(&#39;edit_profile&#39;, views.edit_profile, name=&#39;edit_profile&#39;)  Next to create the edit_profile view in the views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 7</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-7/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Project Proposal Peer Review Todays blog is around reviewing another classmates project proposal. There are quite a lot of good proposals, but the one that I have chosen to review is Stewart&amp;rsquo;s project proposal. His proposal is about building a neural network to recognize and classify a face in an image. The activities he has listed are as follows.
 Read an academic article on face detection Research computer vision and find relevant articles Research academic articles on computer vision Lynda courses  Neural networks and convolutional neural networks essential training Deep learning: face recognition Classify images and detect recognition  CourseRA tutorials  Convolutional neural networks  Exploring and using Azure&amp;rsquo;s cloud based face or computer vision services  As I have a bias for AI, I like this proposal and am glad to see a classmate interested in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 15</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-15/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Profile In the previous blog we implemented the registration functionality. Now to add additional fields when registering and a profile page for users. In this blog we are going to explore extending the user model. The first thing we need to do is to create a new class in the models.py file in our authentication app. To this file we are going to add the following code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 14</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-14/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Registration In the previous blog we covered the basic implementation of authentication using the built-in authentication system of Django. In this blog we are going to cover how to handle user registration. The first thing to do is to add the following line to the urls.py file under our authentication app.
path(&#39;register&#39;, views.register, name=&#39;register&#39;)  Now to create the corresponding view in the views.py file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-2/</guid>
      <description>Docker-compose ~ container_name For my SDV701 assessment 2 we have to build a tiered software. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use Flask for the presentation tier, Flask-restful for the logic tier, and mongodb (via pymongo) for the data tier. I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to use docker and docker-compose since running a mongodb server in docker is as easy as pulling an image from docker-hub. Below is a snippet from the docker-compose.yml file, showing how easy it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 6</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-6/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Interests and non-interests in IT One of the topics that we discussed today in class was things about IT that interest me and the things that don&amp;rsquo;t interest me. We were given the following questions to answer in no more than 10 words.
 The IT area/subject I have most enjoyed is Software development
The IT area/subject I least enjoyed is Systems analysis and design (SYD)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 13</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-13/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Authentication In this blog post we are going to cover the implementation of user authentication. First thing to do is to create a new app via python3 manage.py startapp authentication. Next we need to run python3 manage.py migrate. Then we need to create a super user via python3 manage.py createsuperuser. Now we need to add authentication to the INSTALLED_APPS list in the settings.py file. Once that is done we can start to add the authentication functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 12</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-12/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Assessment 2 Milestone 3 Since I have completed milestone&amp;rsquo;s 1 and 2 for assessment 2 of web701, I am going to start milestone 3 (building the proposed website). I have chosen to use Django since Django is more suitable for a production environment than Flask. Originally I was going to use Django-cms, but quickly found that it would not be as easy to implement some of the features required for the milestone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 5</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-5/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Analyzing Academic Articles Todays blog is about reading and understanding one of the academic articles that I chose for the previous blog. We are to answer the following questions around the article.
 Did the abstract tell you three things I said it should? If not what did it tell you?
 What seems to be the research question(s) they were trying to answer?
 What method(s) did they use to answer the question(s)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 11</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-11/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas ~ Lab 4 In this blog we are going to go through lab 4 which goes into more depth around functions.
The first part of the lab covers configuration injection with environment variables. There are two ways of doing so; at deployment time and using query string and HTTP headers. Environment variables at deployment time are covered in lab 3 when working with write_debug, which is where the environment variable is added to the YAML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-1/</guid>
      <description>Docker-compose In this blog we are going to explore a tool thats apart of the docker ecosystem; docker-compose. &amp;ldquo;Compose is a tool for defining and running multi-container Docker applications.&amp;rdquo; [source] There is an awesome example found on the getting started section, which shows the power of docker-compose. The example is shown below.
app.py
import time import redis from flask import Flask app = Flask(__name__) cache = redis.Redis(host=&#39;redis&#39;, port=6379) def get_hit_count(): retries = 5 while True: try: return cache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 10</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-10/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas Continued ~ Lab 3 In this blog we are going to explore the OpenFaas workshop. Since we already have OpenFaas deployed and running from the previous blog, we are going to skip to lab 3; introduction to functions. OpenFaas provides two ways of creating a new function; using a template, or using an existing binary. I dont have a binary to use, so I am going to be using a template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/docker-0/</guid>
      <description>Docker Back in 2017 I learned about a ton of new and exciting technologies that I had never used or even heard of. One of those technologies is docker. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know of docker, then let me give some background information. &amp;ldquo;Docker is an open platform for developing, shipping, and running applications.&amp;rdquo; [source]. Before we can dive further into what this really means we need to first come to an understanding of containerization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-4/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Academic Publishing Today&amp;rsquo;s blog is about finding two academic research papers of my choice, which as stated in the first res701 blog will be around data science, machine learning, or deep learning. I stumbled across a gentleman by the name of Jürgen Schmidhuber when watching a video on a panel of specialists talking about the current state of AI. At the time I had no clue who he was or what his accomplishments were, but came to know that he was behind the publication of LSTM (long short-term memory) architectures and also the advancements in CNN (convolutional neural networks) architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 9</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-9/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ OpenFaas As stated in the previous blog, the first exposure to serverless was OpenFaaS. Whether its because of bias of the first exposure or because of bias towards docker, I am going to be exploring OpenFaaS for the serverless implementation of assessment three. First thing to do like anything is to head to the documentation section. &amp;ldquo;OpenFaaS (Functions as a Service) is a framework for building serverless functions with Docker and Kubernetes which has first class support for metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 8</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-8/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Serverless For the third assessment we are to choose a web technology to research and implement. It has to be web related, so one of the things that came up when discussing with my tutor was exploring serverless architectures. I have been exposed to serverless before when I was browsing through /r/opensource and came across OpenFaaS. Before we dive any deeper lets come to an understanding of what we really mean when we are talking about serverless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-3/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Credibility How can something be credible? Both the oxford dictionary and merriam-webster define credibility as &amp;ldquo;the quality of being believable&amp;rdquo; [source 1] [source 2] This to me is rather dangerous, since things like vaccine hesitancy have gained traction in recent years. This stems from social platforms giving an amplified voice to those who are not credible, but are accepted as credible by others using the social platform(s) for their source(s) of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 7</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-7/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Web Hosting This blog is going to cover web hosting, to make the website publicly available to the outside world. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about web hosting, nor do I care to go into much detail since this is something that a web developer needs to know. As I stated in the web security blog, I have little interest in web development. That being said hosting the website is something that our tutor wants us to get some experience with so here I am writing a blog about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 6</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-6/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Django-cms, Wagtail &amp;amp; Odoo Last blog I didn&amp;rsquo;t really go into much detail around getting the Django based CMSs or Odoo installed/running. This blog is going to cover those in more detail. To recap, as stated in the previous blog, I have no experience with Django but do have some with Odoo. The reason I am working with Django and not the framework I&amp;rsquo;ve been using (Flask) is because Django is a fullstack framwork, where Flask is only a microframework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-2/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Paradigms Postmodernism is a word that I have heard people like Jordan Peterson use but is not a word that I never investigated. It just so happens that postmodernism is one of the paradigms that we talked about in class. The other paradigms are classical and social. One of the take homes is to choose one of the paradigms, describe it, explain what it can be used for, and why I like/dislike the paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello_rust.rs</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/hello-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/hello-rust/</guid>
      <description>Why Rust? The first question anyone might ask themselves when they read the title. This is an extremely valid question, since why if one could learn something as simple as Python, would one want to learn a language like Rust? I know this because that was the first question that I asked. The answer is not entirely formulated as I still learn new and exciting things everyday.
The why&amp;rsquo;s What I can say is that for one Rust is fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 5</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-5/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Virtual Machines and Docker Class was mainly reviewing the mock projects, so this blog is going to be dedicated to the virtual machines that I use on virtualbox. For the second milestone we have to describe three frameworks, two of which were prompted in class; laravel (PHP), and meteor (NodeJS). Its times like these that I am thankful for virtual machines. Im not sure how difficult these were to install and get running on windows machines and I dont care to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-4/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ S(ecure) SH(ell) Today in Web701 we learned about SSH so that we can access a remote server for hosting out web technologies on. I have had experience with SSH before since that is how I connect to my raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s and my onion omega, though I prefer the terminal SSH cli to a GUI like putty. Yet another advantage of Linux is that distributions come with SSH pre-installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-1/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Ontology &amp;amp; Epistemology Today in class the tutor had a set of questions that he wanted us to break up into groups and answer. Reflecting on these questions has only increased the amount questions rather than provide truthful or even a slightly understandable answers. In saying that they are also extremely interesting questions that have a much deeper meaning than anyone could ever percieve or come to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-3/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Security Though web development is not a main focus (or at least front end), I don&amp;rsquo;t spend much time investigating many web technologies/concepts. That being said computer security is a general topic that interests me, and learning the subset internet security is something that one should know. Internet security involves WWW (world wide web), browser, and networking security. Since the internet is insecure, internet securities &amp;ldquo;objective is to establish rules and measures to use against attacks over the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-2/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Comparison of frameworks and CMS Todays class covers a comparison of frameworks and CMS. The tutor gave access to an online document with the following questions. We split up into groups, so I will review the answers my group (Bryce, Finn, Deja, and myself).
What is a CMS? A platform that allows non-developers to manage the content of a website
How many are there? Over 9000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Res701 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/res701-0/</guid>
      <description>Research 701 ~ Day 0 Res701 is another required class for my bachelor of IT course. This class is based around academic research, where we look at/review academic papers/research methodologies and write blogs about them. Blogs have never been my strong point so I am going to put 110% effort into ensuring consistentcy for this class. I already know what area I am going to be focusing on (data science, machine learning and deep learning), so in that regard I am already ahead of the curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-1/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Frameworks and VirtualBox Today in web701 we covered the frameworks and softwares that are going to be used for the assessment. The frameworks are laravel (an open-source PHP web framework) and meteor (an open-source NodeJS web framework). The softwares are XAMPP (an open-source web server) and composer (a dependancy manager for PHP). I am going to be installing these on a ubuntu virtual machine, so the first thing I need to do is install virtualbox on my manjaro partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-0/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 Web development is a required class for my major (software development) in the bachelor of IT. The 701 class is based around information architecture, CMS (content management systems), frameworks and website security. A CMS is essentially a platform which allows a user to change the website without touching any code, usually the form of drag and drops. I don&amp;rsquo;t program using PHP at all, and don&amp;rsquo;t really have any interest in web development so I am going to see if I can use Odoo, since it has a website module that is a CMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 5</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-5/</guid>
      <description>Day 6 Today was the final day of the RYLA trip. No personal training today, just the usual banana/apple for breakfast then straight into speakers.
The first speaker of the day was Kingseley, the event organizer and another favorite of mine. His talk was on gaining information, something I strive to do everyday. There are various ways of gathering information, a few examples can be found below &amp;hellip;
 Reading Listening/watching videos Talking to people Interviewing  Then he explained the various types of questions which include but are not limited to &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 4</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-4/</guid>
      <description>Day 5 After needed sleep and again waking up to the usual 7am personal training and a breakfast of a banana/apple. The first speaker of the day was another favorite, Michelle Sharp, the CEO of Kilmarnock. Kilmarnock is a social enterprise (started by Christobel Robinson), which by Michelle&amp;rsquo;s definition is a business model that takes on social issues. She told us about the story of how after 50+ years, Kilmarnock was about to close its doors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 3</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-3/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 Today as normal we woke and gathered at 7am for personal training, though today&amp;rsquo;s pt was just yoga (which was actually really nice). Then for breakfast I ate the usually banana and apple. Today was the high-ropes course, which I was rather excited for since I had never done something like that before. The first thing we did when we got their was put sunscreen on cause damn it was hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 2</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 The morning started of the same as the previous, we all woke and gathered at 7am for personal training with Honour, but this time she delegated 2 people to be the ones to organize the exercises. Our group was with Demi who had a great warm up idea where we had to run around in a circle and when she said a command we had to do the appropriate animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-1/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 The morning started at 7am where we would do personal training with Honour. Then afterwards was morning breakfast. I am not one who usually eats breakfast, but I figured I would need the energy so I ate a banana. Our first speaker of the day was a person from the NZ defense force. I will have to re-iterate this section with his name as I cannot remember it and didn&amp;rsquo;t take the opprotunity to write it down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryla 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ryla-0/</guid>
      <description>Rotary Youth Leadership Association ~ Day 1 Rotary is a group of individuals that come together and help the local community through various means. Both of my parents are active members of the Wakatu Nelson branch, where they meet every Friday morning at 7am. I have been a few times and have enjoyed myself everytime. One of the members, Delise, told me about this camp of sorts called RYLA (Rotary Youth Leadership Association).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ss-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/ss-0/</guid>
      <description>Self Study 1 2018 is over and 2019 has just begun. I have learned a lot over the past couple of years and still have much more to learn. For this reason I have decided to make a tag called self-study. There is a list that I have started to make of the various skills/technologies/libraries/concepts/etc&amp;hellip; that I have picked up over the last 3 years which I will be improving upon in this sub-set of blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bmus</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</guid>
      <description>Bmus ~ Back Me Up Scotty Taking backups of devices is something that more often than not people don&amp;rsquo;t do, and this includes myself. Prior to my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s I never took backups or even thought about them. Looking back I reee internally everytime I think about how much I would have lost if something had happened to my laptops or desktops over the years. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like the 2015 me, take regular backups&amp;hellip; Ever since a friend of mine, Nick got me into Linux I have been learning new things everyday, from built in commands, to the various things that can be done from the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inotebook</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/inotebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/inotebook/</guid>
      <description>I(llusionists) Notebook If you have seen the Prestige, then this program will look familiar. Inotebook is a personal notebook that is encrypted with the vigenere cipher. A vigenere cipher is similar to a caesar cipher (where characters are shifted by a certain offset), but the vigenere cipher uses a key to determine the offset rather than a number. The key is repeated to the length of the message, then each character of the message is offset by the character of the key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partitioning</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/partitioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/partitioning/</guid>
      <description>Partitioning Partitioning? No not mathematics partitions, computer partitions. More specifically hardware partitions (in my case a microSD card). I am officially put off GUIs and am taking a hiatus from them. My raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s microSDD card isn&amp;rsquo;t being used at the moment, so I am formatting it to be used as storage for pcap files that I am capturing on my network. Perfect time to learn how to partition drives from the terminal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmux</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/tmux/</guid>
      <description>Tmux - Terminal Multiplexer If you&amp;rsquo;re like me then you use a terminal a lot. If you were me 20 minutes ago then you would also have multiple terminal tabs open with various applications running. I had heard of an application from some of my peers before about the ability to open multiple terminal panes within the same terminal window. For a while I didn&amp;rsquo;t look into it, but then (about 20 minutes ago) I had enough of swapping between terminal tabs and the editor I had been using (vscode).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 12 ~ The Future</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-12/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ The Future The project is now coming to an end, and I find myself writing my last blog which I am titling &amp;ldquo;The Future&amp;rdquo; to discuss my plans from here. Now that I know the basics of Odoo and how to deploy an instance, I will most certainly be using Odoo for the infrastructure of all my personal business ventures (like Ponte Posterum). Krupesh has offered me a permanent position at Venus, so I will be continuing with him and helping to build some amazing stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 11 ~ Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-11/</guid>
      <description>Project 702 ~ Problem Solving and Facing Difficulties It never occured to me that problem solving was a skill, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t up until recent that I have come to understand that it falls under conceptual skills. I learned during my studies at Nelson Marlborough Institute of Technology that problem solving is in fact the only skill required to be in the IT industry. By my definition or perception all one really needs to know in order to be a good problem solver is how to structure a web search on duckduckgo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 10 ~ Creating an Odoo Module</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-10/</guid>
      <description>PRJ701 - Creating an Odoo Module One of the most powerful things that Odoo brings is the fact that it is open-source. This allows developers like myself to extend the existing structure to fit any use case. To make it even better, Odoo has taken it a step further and provided a built in way to generating the skeleton of an entirely new module. This is done via the scaffold flag when executing odoo-bin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 9 ~ Sales Module</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-9/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Sales Module Since the module to be developed involves the sales module, I will be dedicating a blog to exploring the various components that make up the module. For me to better understand what it is I am manipulating or changing I will go through the processes that the sales module provides; half the battle is understanding how it all comes together. One of the resources available to me is the Odoo training center, which contains various tutorials on the different modules, including one for sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 8 - Setting Up Odoo</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-8/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Setting Up Odoo The first thing I need to do is to ssh into the linux virtual machine that I created on Azure and install a few dependancies. Before I do that I will start with a simple sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get upgrade. Now to install the following dependancies; git python3.5 python3.5-dev virtualenv vim postgresql xz-utils wget fontconfig libfreetype6 libx11-6 libxext6 libxrender1 node-less node-clean-css xfonts-75dpi libxml2-dev libxslt1-dev libevent-dev libsasl2-dev libssl1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 7 ~ Sales Order XML Parse</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-7/</guid>
      <description>Project 702 ~ Sales Order XML Parse One of the stages in the project is to create a module which provides the functionality of automatically generating a sales order based on the values from an XML file retrived from an FTP server. Before I create a module I am going to create a test-driven example using the standard library ftplib which provides an FTP client, containing the functions (nlist and retrbinary) that are necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 6 ~ Vim</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-6/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Vim I am sure if you have heard of vim then you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard good things. I mean hell there are jokes about just exiting vim. Vim (Vi IMproved) is a clone of the vi text editor made by Bill Joy for Unix. When I was first exposed to a text editor (nano) I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very fond of it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense why I would use a text editor over what I was currently using at the time (atom).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 5 ~ Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-5/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Proxmox Networking is one of the IT sectors that I have yet to spend much time in. My only exposure has been a NET501 class where we covered the basics of things like booting a virtual machine, routers/IPs, certificates, dhcp, and a few others. Since then I haven&amp;rsquo;t really touched anything to do with networking except for creation/use of virtual machines on the cloud platforms (GCP, AWS and Azure).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 4 ~ XML</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-4/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ XML (Extensive Markup Language) I&amp;rsquo;m personally not a fan of XML as I feel it can get to complicated and cluttered, although I do come from a bias of JSON. Even so again this is what I have to learn, so learn I shall. XML to me is just HTML but with more tags so picking up XML shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too difficult. For anything I normally look for documentation or blogs with examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 3 - PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-3/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ PostgreSQL PostgreSQL is an open source, no-sql (object-relational) database (ORDBMS) which is the db Odoo is built upon. I only have experience with MySQL which is entirely different since, its MySQL relation database management system (RDBMS). I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually used or played around with Postgres so I will be utilizing an awesome blog I found (via quick duckduckgo(ddg) search) which is by the Nanyang Technological University. This blog contains 6 sections with great snippets of quick refence information (I purposely left out the section about PHP cause don&amp;rsquo;t touch that stuff with a 20ft pole).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 2 ~ Azure</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Azure Part of the stack that is being used for this project is Azure. I am not a fan of microsoft so my opinion on anything to do with them is not positive. This is the cloud provider that Krupesh has chosen to go with however, so I will learn it anyway. Azure (like most cloud providers) gives 200 credits which are only valid for 30 days (GCP and AWS are both a year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 1 ~ Python(3)</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-1/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Python (3) I attended a Python meetup group in May 18th 2017. Krupesh was giving a presentation on Python and what it is capable of. The day after this meeting I decided I was going to start learning Python. The first thing I did was make a file containing the basic syntax of the Python programming language. This would become the foundation for what I know today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 0 ~ Odoo ~ Venus Informatics</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-0/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Odoo ~ Venus Informatics My 3rd year project proposal started to form without me really knowing it during my first year DAT501(database) class, which at the time was taught by my now best friend Krupesh Desai. At the time Krupesh was working at the NMDHB(Nelson Marlborough District Health Board) on a solution to merge all of the DHB&amp;rsquo;s throughout New Zealand onto one platform. Around May the following year I had met Krupesh again at an ITP (IT Professionals) meeting where I asked him a question on feasability of a malware detecting AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello_self.me</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello World! What better way to start a blog off than the classical way of starting in programming ~ the ol&amp;rsquo; Hello World! My name is Daniel, I go by OGLinuk as my online handler, and I have a raging passion for IT. Technology has been apart of my life for as long as I can remember, starting with an old windows 98 desktop and an N64. This is where my passion for gaming began, with classics like 007 golden eye, banjo-kazooie, diddy kong racing, donkey kong 64, legoland, and so many more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>