<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:12:33 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PTP</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/project/ptp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/project/ptp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBH</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/project/sbh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/project/sbh/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:12:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</guid>
      <description>Nginx ~ Deploying a Go Web Application Nginx is another one of those technologies that I&amp;rsquo;ve known of for a while, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to dig into. This blog will cover how to deploy a basic Golang web application on a $5/month ubuntu 18.04 vm hosted by Digital Ocean. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a really good blog by Michael Okoh which is what I am going to learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega2 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:46:09 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/omega2-0/</guid>
      <description>Onion Omega 2 During a Python meetup one of my tutors Mark showed me a new device he had purchased from kickstarter called the onion omega 2. All that I knew at the time was that it was a smaller version of a raspberry pi. When I first got my hands on one I found out it was so much more under the hood. The first things to note is the unit itself needs another component (a dock).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goccer</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/goccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 20:27:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/goccer/</guid>
      <description>Goccer ~ Go Concurrent Web Crawler In one of the classes during my bachelor of IT, I started making my first program in Golang. That first program is what is now know as goccer. The idea behind the program was inspired by my fascination of web crawling. This blog is not going to cover every part of goccer, but will cover the key components. It will also cover the issues I ran into and the solution(s) that I used to overcome the problem(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bmus</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/bmus/</guid>
      <description>Bmus ~ Back Me Up Scotty Taking backups of devices is something that more often than not people don&amp;rsquo;t do, and this includes myself. Prior to my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s I never took backups or even thought about them. Looking back I reee internally everytime I think about how much I would have lost if something had happened to my laptops or desktops over the years. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like the 2015 me, take regular backups&amp;hellip; Ever since a friend of mine, Nick got me into Linux I have been learning new things everyday, from built in commands, to the various things that can be done from the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>