<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Hosting on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/web-hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Hosting on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/web-hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 20</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-20/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Heroku and Web Hosting We wrapped up the web implementation in the last blog with the addition of the auction system. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy the website to a web hosting service. There are two options that are available for the deployment, my tutors remote server, or a PaaS (Platform as a Service) provider like Heroku.
I want to get experience in both so I will deploy on both, but since the dependancies I require for the website are not yet installed on the tutor&amp;rsquo;s server I will start with deploying on Heroku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 7</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-7/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Web Hosting This blog is going to cover web hosting, to make the website publicly available to the outside world. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about web hosting, nor do I care to go into much detail since this is something that a web developer needs to know. As I stated in the web security blog, I have little interest in web development. That being said hosting the website is something that our tutor wants us to get some experience with so here I am writing a blog about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>