<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Ocean on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/digital-ocean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Ocean on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:34:19 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/digital-ocean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx 1</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:34:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-1/</guid>
      <description>Nginx ~ Subdomains and a Blog In the previous blog we explored serving a Go web application with Nginx on Digital Ocean. This blog is going to cover how to host a static website on a subdomain. One of the things I did not cover in the last blog is how to point to your domain name with Digital Ocean. For more on this please refer to this blog that I found/used originally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx 0</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:12:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/nginx-0/</guid>
      <description>Nginx ~ Deploying a Go Web Application Nginx is another one of those technologies that I&amp;rsquo;ve known of for a while, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to dig into. This blog will cover how to deploy a basic Golang web application on a $5/month ubuntu 18.04 vm hosted by Digital Ocean. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a really good blog by Michael Okoh which is what I am going to learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web701 22</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/web701-22/</guid>
      <description>Web Development 701 ~ Deploying with Digital Ocean Now that we have built the function, which was covered in the last post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy it. For deployment we will be using digital ocean for a couple of reasons. First it&amp;rsquo;s much easier than setting up instances in the larger cloud providers like GCP, AWS, or Azure. Second digital ocean has an OpenFaas one-click droplet.
The first thing to do is to ssh into the droplet via ssh root@&amp;lt;IP address&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>