<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Ponte Posterum</title>
    <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Ponte Posterum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oglinuk.github.io/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 10 ~ Creating an Odoo Module</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-10/</guid>
      <description>PRJ701 - Creating an Odoo Module One of the most powerful things that Odoo brings is the fact that it is open-source. This allows developers like myself to extend the existing structure to fit any use case. To make it even better, Odoo has taken it a step further and provided a built in way to generating the skeleton of an entirely new module. This is done via the scaffold flag when executing odoo-bin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 6 ~ Vim</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-6/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Vim I am sure if you have heard of vim then you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard good things. I mean hell there are jokes about just exiting vim. Vim (Vi IMproved) is a clone of the vi text editor made by Bill Joy for Unix. When I was first exposed to a text editor (nano) I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very fond of it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense why I would use a text editor over what I was currently using at the time (atom).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 2 ~ Azure</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-2/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Azure Part of the stack that is being used for this project is Azure. I am not a fan of microsoft so my opinion on anything to do with them is not positive. This is the cloud provider that Krupesh has chosen to go with however, so I will learn it anyway. Azure (like most cloud providers) gives 200 credits which are only valid for 30 days (GCP and AWS are both a year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prj701 0 ~ Odoo ~ Venus Informatics</title>
      <link>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oglinuk.github.io/post/prj701-0/</guid>
      <description>Project 701 ~ Odoo ~ Venus Informatics My 3rd year project proposal started to form without me really knowing it during my first year DAT501(database) class, which at the time was taught by my now best friend Krupesh Desai. At the time Krupesh was working at the NMDHB(Nelson Marlborough District Health Board) on a solution to merge all of the DHB&amp;rsquo;s throughout New Zealand onto one platform. Around May the following year I had met Krupesh again at an ITP (IT Professionals) meeting where I asked him a question on feasability of a malware detecting AI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>